<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2016-2022 Yoshimi project <willgodfrey@musically.me.uk> -->
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>net.sourceforge.projects.yoshimi.desktop</id>
  <metadata_license>CC-BY-4.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-2.0+</project_license>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
  <name>Yoshimi</name>
  <summary>A Software Synthesizer for Linux</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
    Yoshimi is a MIDI software synthesizer for Linux. It synthesizes in real time, can run polyphonic and/or monophonic in multiple simultaneous patches in one or more MIDI channels and has broad microtonal capability. It includes extensive additive, subtractive, and PAD synth capabilities which can be run simultaneously within the same patch. It also has comprehensive effects capabilities.
    </p>
    <p>
    Originally based on the 2.4.0 version of ZynAddSubFX (Copyright 2002-2009 Nasca Octavian Paul), development of Yoshimi has continued for quite a while now in its own direction. Originally these included major optimizations for audio and MIDI performance. More recently there has been progressive development of user-level access to all controls, including command line access. Since V1.5.0 there is full Midi Learn capability.
    </p>
    <p>
    In the V1.7.x series ALSA MIDI can search for and connect to all viable sources, almost all controls have been made realtime, both key and channel aftertouch have been implemented and there is now the ability to change the panning law. Refinement continues, both visually and within the code.
    </p>
    <p>
    Version 2.0 brings fully resizable windows, MIDI sync for LFOs, and extensions to panning control.
    </p>
    <p>
    Version 2.1.0 extends MIDI sync for Effects where relevant, and adds extensions to NRPNs. There is also a new HTML User Guide.
    </p>
    <p>
    Version 2.2.0 sees a major revision of the PadSynth engine allowing significant morphing of the wavetables in real-time.
    </p>
  </description>
  <releases>
​    <release type="stable" version="2.2.1" date="2022-7-25" />
​  </releases>
  <provides>
    <binary>yoshimi</binary>
  </provides>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
       <image>https://a.fsdn.com/con/app/proj/yoshimi/screenshots/Main.png</image>
       <caption>The main window showing Yoshimi running</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
       <image>https://a.fsdn.com/con/app/proj/yoshimi/screenshots/Mixer.png</image>
       <caption>Yoshimi in action</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
       <image>https://a.fsdn.com/con/app/proj/yoshimi/screenshots/MidiLearn.png</image>
       <caption>The MIDI-learn window.</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <categories>
     <category>AudioVideo</category>
     <category>Audio</category>
     <category>Midi</category>
     <category>Synthesiser</category>
  </categories>
  <url type="homepage">https://sourceforge.net/projects/yoshimi/</url>
</component>
